so wanted to bring up to the the noble
method what is the noble method and that
the wise person the stream enter has
attained hmm or discovered so to speak
he's understood what the method is for
the cultivation of the pond he's
understood what if that method that now
he must exercise so that he can
cultivate and develop that Nibbana which
he knows so what is that noble message
it's not he's watching counting of the
breath or watching your feet repeating a
mantra so what is it
so here's a suitor I'll put in the
description the suture okay and what is
the noble method that he has clearly
seen and thoroughly penetrated with
wisdom the ideas understood here
householder the noble disciple attends
properly that you only saw money socotra
so he attends closely to dependent
origination with their sockets and
places so that's their that's it but
it's and father doesn't matter how
differently you find it described in the
suitors it's always described upon the
same principle as the Buddha himself
said which is with this this is both the
present closer raise the relationship of
determination so the reason why I'm
saying that is because there is a
certainly quite established contemporary
ideals but it's some part of being an
explanation of rebirth and so on you can
check out a lot of talks on the on the
website but it's a part of it in brief
here it's actually a principle of
attending knowing how to attend things
properly that's a petition father is seeing the
that's a petition father is seeing the
present the enduring necessary condition
for the presently enduring necessary
state so the present the enduring
necessary condition for your craving on
account of which you suffer is a present
enduring feeling for example so with
this this is with this this is the
problem with this this is the party to
some part with the grain as it was
described off so then by seeing the
necessary condition you get to approach
the problem that is so the problem of
suffering calling of aging sickness
birth and so on but it doesn't mean you
need to go through all the fat 12
factors or sixteen factors or sometimes
the attractor means you need to see the
principle with clarity and then it will
that seeing the principle clarity
results in uprooting the our servers and
the the exercising of that principle it
is the method is the method which means
it's how can you exercise the principle
of right attention only by finding out
what that principle is yeah and that's
something like if you do this method
will then result in understanding the
clarity of dispassion disenchantment and
so on but you can't have a method of oh
these are the prescribed set of motions
and things you do they will then
magically arrive at understanding you
see it's it's really interpreted the
other way around
I watch my breath then I get the
understanding yeah and then and then
basically the work is done forming it
through that understanding that I
haven't like and even within mundane
terms the only way to develop
understanding is to try what keep making
effort to understand which means you
need to know what needs to be understood
be clear about it clarified more
question it and then you might arrive at
understanding even in lay terms like
about Dhamma practice if person is not
interesting down legislators when it
comes to understanding there is no
prescribed set so just do this write
this down then look at the cadet and it
will result in understanding now you
know that even in education you can be
presented with information you can
memorize information you can learn how
information works
that doesn't mean you understood the
principle of it and that's the
difference between good students and bad
students or like students that Excel are
the ones who actually start
understanding things as opposed to just
memorize heavy their parotid art and
move on and there is no method of that
mechanical nature that can result in on
the understanding automatically is just
impossible
so when it comes to Dhamma it's even
more so because like the understanding
is the liberation thoroughly
understanding the nature experience
means you are another hand but it's the
same understanding by the way the
principle of understanding is still the
same it's not somehow we abandon the
reason a rational thought of what
understanding is when it comes to
practice of Dhamma and then
understanding is something mystical if
it's mystical it's not understood as
simple as that that's the definition of
mysticism unclear ambiguous mystique
so so the point is when it comes to like
somebody who wants to practice the
Dhamma in order to develop the right
view you need to make the effort
understand what the principle of that is
Methodist yeah so if you understand then
ah that dependent origination or
whichever way it's translated means you
got the right view but and you also
means you you you know the Four Noble
Truths and it also means you know the
way out of suffering first thing you can
you can have that the idea of that you
can even you can have the right idea of
what right view is exactly very close
Hey but now that doesn't mean you need
actually you need to have the right idea
because if you don't have the right idea
how can you then understand the
principle behind the idea but obviously
you can have the right idea but if you
never make the effort to understand the
principle behind it you won't understand
it either so you need to have the right
idea and then you need to make the
effort to understand the principle now
you might ask so how do I know when I
understood it he's still just an idea or
understanding he's sort of taking place
well you would know if you are unable to
suffer that's that's the thing you can
have the right idea but you're not gonna
have the fruits of that right idea you
meet it no think so you don't know is
this the right idea well it's the most
right idea that it's the closest that I
clothing to be right yes oh no what so
yeah but that's not enough no what okay
now I'm clear about but it's a bother
let's move on okay if you're truly clear
about petition but about the idea of
dependent origination
you would be unable to suffer amidst
suffering is that the case you have to
ask yourself honestly and transparently
am I unable to suffer amid things that
used to make me suffer and trigger
emotions and so on now I just AM am
unable to suffer not like I prevent
myself from experiencing these things I
tried to hide away or explain them to
myself or it's it's you know Superman
it's not a big deal no no am i how much
am i affected by it in the first place
that should be a measure of whether
you're progressing rightly or not
because if you are understanding but
it's about that photo which which means
you you will be unable to be affected as
much as before and when you start
wrecking it and the immediately
confidence comes ah I am unable to be
disturbed not because I'm trying to hide
myself away from the disturbance it's
simply because I'm basically I'm above
the disturbance on account of my
understanding
yeah how does mind standing relate to
somewhere suffering does it not even
relate because then you know how does it
relate let me figure it out how it
relates like is my understanding of
these are these ideas that I have are
they free me
are they preventing me from being able
to be disturbed by the suffering in the
first place regardless of whether I know
the connection between the tore not that
I mean how much can I suffer and if
you're understanding things that should
be diminishing you can't say exactly to
what it towards the quantify the extent
but you know that you are less disturbed
disturbance persists less and less
arises less frequently but how do you
know that it is the right idea
when you have no results well yeah is it
possibly well maybe that's what we keep
saying that that's why it's impossible
to become sotapanna accidentally to get
the right view accidentally like oh I
just done this in one now I know because
you have no criteria you have no
immediate measure so why would you then
be doing that thing when you can't even
discern it as something to be done let
alone keep repeating it without a patent
result you keep why would you keep
repeating that right view because you
need to repeat that idea that you
clarify once you need to repeat maybe
millions of times depending on where you
are at internally but you need to keep
repeating so the only one reason you'll
be repeating it is out of faith are the
sufficient faith in that like
intellectual recognition that this might
be closest to the truth the only way to
verify that is to commit and start
repeating it and read drilling let the
training he trains himself does I will
not figure this as much I will not
regard this as permanent
he all N or not like once or twice three
times who knows how many times
well the Buddha says how many times for
seven years seven months who knows but
basically you just you can't do it I'll
do this module you just have to do it
until the results take place but he also
he gives different ways to do this yeah
sure but it's doing the same principle
doing the same thing in but you can do
it
the surest way to lose sati putana comes
in yes you cannot it attend to you on
the basis of the bargaining the
principle you can do the basic feelings
on the base of the mind on the basis of
the thoughts what you can attend to the
breath but if the principle you're
looking for so it's like when you
practice my friends to the ball dinner
or I'm watching sensations and it's just
observing sense of touch sensations of
touch me perception of touch sensations
through my legs and back it's literally
perception of touch nothing else so
somehow perception of touch results in
this transcendental experience of
understanding no it's just mechanically chasing for
no it's just mechanically chasing for
the novelty experiences realizing your
right view you just you know textures
arrive you because you don't have it and
you're not gonna have it because you're
not looking to find it and you find it
when you understand the principle off
off but its own father because that's
when Ananda who you know who had the
right view for like over 20 years when
he was sitting that time with the Buddha
and said I mean it's amazing like but
it's the clearest thing possible it's
right there in your face with this this
is it's just it's so easy since always
there and it will say no don't say that
it's easy like it's easy for you because
you've been basically you're the study
twenty years ago and ever since you just
be fortifying it but it's because of
that very thing that I teach so far the
principle that people don't understand
that's why all the demons of suffering
and some sorrows and everything else so
in other word it is so it's the closest
thing to you and that's why it's
invisible people are not used to looking
so closely so just but not attending so
closely and when I say are standing
close that I mean attending to the
particular details but more like wait
I'm attending to this on account of what
what is the peripheral of this currently
air is an attention perspective on your
attention what's the perspective on
unaccounted yeah what's the perspective
on things that I'm currently attending
to me so like you feeling for example
I'm feeling upset okay so you can now
choose the direction of attending the
upset and what has seemingly caused it
what you perceived at the time who said
what when what you should do next time I
you should decided all of that is all
we did the context that you are affected
by the upset it's unpleasant and now
you're trying to get their displeasure
because you can then stop wait I how
many times I chased down psychology
psychology of why I got upset I should
have done this should have done that
next time I'll do this all in order to
prevent that upset happening to you or
you can choose to attend wait what if I
don't give in to trying to get rid of
the pain of upset but see what else is
there is a necessary basis for that
upset to take place that's now the
different direction that's direction of
broader context on account of cuddly
reason upset which then starts including
your need to get the rid of the upset
because it's unpleasant which you won't
be seeing if you just give in and follow
the thought of upset down the line
wherever it takes you so the context
it's kind of rediscovered on a broader
terms because there's always a context
even when you choose to psychologize the
context is trying to get rid of the pain
but you're unaware of it so there is no
limit to how much you can develop
context rightly but doesn't matter how
much you develop the context for how
much you lose the context the principle
of with context this is the direction
stay is the same with this this is so
you just want to reverse the order so to
speak and not go with the grain is the
Buddha would say context of upset means
get rid of the upset for an untrained
mind so you learn that that doesn't work
you use your intelligence your reason to
see that that doesn't work so what if I
try the opposite so context of upset
need to get rid of the upset restrain
the need to get rid of the upset within
the context of upset so you start
swimming against the grain against the
current and then the more you do that
the more familiar then you become with
the context of upset that you were
blindly just trying to get rid of and
then you realize well wait the only
reason I'm upset the only reason I
suffer unkind of this upset is because
I'm trying to get rid of the upset out
of my view that this must be removed
that's the perspective that you that's
the perspective you'll gain if you start
swimming upstream but for that you need
that restraint of
you need faith because you have no
verification that upstream will
guarantee results of fear from upset but
that faith how much of that faith you
require is determine of how much of your
intellectual capacity and reasoning you
have on account of which you understood
that this is most likely to make sense
that's like hmm induce certain on a base
of reasoning induced like up as a
premise which is the safest one you
can't know for sure beforehand
that's that's the the insufficiency of
Reason by itself you cannot reason the
extent of why you should repeat the
reason so you need to have faith that
your reasoning was accurate enough to
keep repeating it and then you get the
results that the direct results of
repetition of reasons not just once
reason twice reason three times reason
like repeating the same reflection and
drilling it and drilling it and making
it resist that's why that Dhamma if you
do it is beyond reason now because it's
unreasonable but because it you need to
reason and rationally recognize what is
for your welfare what is good what
should be like heat heated to and done
and then you need to repeat it and you
can't reason them if you're like pure
logical mind that just reasons reasons
accurately you can't reason why you
should repeat this same reflection same
reasoning for seven years because there
is no immediate result that can then
give your feedback for your reason but
if you do it out of faith without
sacrificing your reason which is we made
a parry detection is necessary so you
don't sacrifice the reason you even like
take it even further and just keep
repeating the same reason out of faith
you'll get the result of the right view
how long well that's where the faith
comes in in the same sense you come to
see a doctor you tried so many doctors
so now you heard about such a doctor and
you haven't tried that treatment and
based on kind of trial and error that
you learn on a kind of trying other
doctors you sort of induce a conclusion
that there is a good chance that he
might right he doesn't fit into anything wrong
right he doesn't fit into anything wrong
that you've done before seems to be the
opposite so you can go you can oh you
can reason they did make sense but that
in itself will not cure you you need to
go and start doing what the doctor
prescribed and you cannot reason that
that would be the right thing to do you
can reason that it's going to be the
least likely thing that's wrong but you
need to start doing it to see whether it
actually cures you're not and that's
exactly and when it fuse you the fact
that you're now healthy cute has not
been you haven't obtained it by mere
reasoning alone as the Buddha said
Dhamma cannot be obtained by near
reasoning alone that's what I attack of
a Chara means it's beyond mere reason as
in you use the reason and then you keep
repeating the reason and then you get
cured and now you you'd have not arrived
there it wouldn't be true to say or I
arrived Alise cure simply by reasoning
that that's the cure now that's what
brought you to the cure clear authentic
transparent reasoning but then a
repetition of that cure is both curio
repetition of the reason repetition of
the reason yes exactly yes
so right like you you reason the
principle that the necessity of craving
for suffering like did you have a say in
how your feelings arise
no you just resist them or won them why
is that so use your intellect your
reason to clarify reflection of it and
now you get a sense of okay so when the
feeling arises if it's Pleasant I should
not lean towards it if it's unpleasant I
shouldn't lean away from it
what if I make the effort now to
maintain that as a context as a
reflection as a state of mind that I
arrived at on account of reasoning it
rightly and if you do maintain it you
will appear swimming basically against
the craving and when you reach the
sufficient point of diminishing of
cleaning you will then recognize it and
that's where you verified your reason
for yourself sorta but it yeah that's
why I nobody can be my guide anymore
because now you have discovered the
principle with this this is and that is
your guide there's no doubt anymore you
cannot doubt that
you cannot doubt it so that that is a
noble method the closest you can say to
method is trying to endure for
understanding is trying to understand
time to understand what good question
read the sutras you'll see what you need
to understand and then repeating this
and then keep doing it as I said the
measure of understanding is not when you
get a clear idea about understanding
it's when you cannot suffer anymore when
you have no passion left anymore that's
the measure of the extent of your
understanding that stays the pendulum
ooty other hand the type of practice
what type basically certain people are
either are a hunch it through as when
you say resolve upon wisdom so literally
you have such a clarity of insight and
wisdom but you haven't done it long
enough to uproot the are servers in you
like sotapanna sakagami on egami they
haven't done it long enough so some
people would just stick to it
like you know with a bit of they know
out of faith now that they've confirmed
so they're confident that they they
stick to these reflections this kind of
practice it will result in uprooting
greed aversion delusion because they
already seen it for themselves to some
extent but then the other type is who
would like emphasize that rationale
clarity of that principle and then
literally make a determination upon
maintaining it at any expense at every
other expense they just maintain the
context of with this this is or any
other aspect of that wisdom so resolved
upon that wisdom long enough your inner
and so resolved upon the clarity of that
idea long enough you will be an aren't
they maintained mindfulness example that
through that idea they maintain sense
restraint through that idea Samadhi
through that idea well maintaining that
idea is Kapur composure here keeping the
radio composed which is a definition of
Samadhi
so that's that's what means demise
beyond reason not without reason beyond
reason means small as the buddha said
not attainable by me by reason alone or
by mere reasoning but often people who
jump into conclusion ah the Dhamma
cannot be reasoned thus dhamma is
unreasonable so making mystical and
ambiguous but you just need to read the
sutras and you see it can very much be
reasoned the Buddha will often say well
if the other Brahmins and asset is ask
you this you should then in return ask
them that well if that's your premise
why is this your conclusion and so it's
just pure clear authentic reasoning now
because you just look for faults or you
want to defend yourself like
irrationally but because you rationally
understand the place where they come
from and you rationally understanding
why it's inadequate like when when
Giants would claim they're omniscient
they see and here they see a note all
the time and the Buddha would say well
if somebody claims that you should ask
them why that follower of their teaching
who see and here who see and know
everything all the time why did they get
into accidents why do they fall into
pits why did they get attacked by dogs
because they would have foreseen these
things and they would have avoided them
everybody would avoid those things and
then they try to say well no it's
because you know they choose to go
whatever they try to like now
irrationally rationalize it so do you
read a circus and it's very much
reasonable but that doesn't mean that
mere reason is enough that's why we know
that logician read the sutras
narrator dimensions it he said oh this
is just a mere tautology the whole
suitors are just tautological statements
and that is true if you never if you
never think there is anything more than
just getting the idea of understanding
that stands for understanding so they
are the adult tautological ideas if
you're free from craving you will not be
a victim to craving animal right so you
get that on the level of idea but if you
have no faith now to assume that there
is maybe more to that idea as in more to
be developed you'll stop there
and that's what like a person who puts a
reason and only reason as the sole
criteria can never arrive a dumber
because yes the idea of it is perfectly
reasonable and self-explanatory almost
so what else is missing there it's the
repetition of that idea that misses
because your experience is still
experience of craving with craving with
passion with greed with aversion with
illusion so you have the idea that
absence of craving means you're not
liable to the pressure of craving
anymore which means you will not suffer
on account of it okay so now the idea
that I have clear idea of craving is to
be abandoned I must actually cultivate
Bhavana I must keep repeating it now
just get the idea and be and take it for
granted that now that has been
completely understood which is what a
person as I said who puts rationalizing
and thinking
first and foremost can never arrive at
that's why they can never commit to any
degree of faith even if it's literally a
faith to a doctor nobody's asking you to
like the problem with other religions is
when they ask for faith they ask it at
the expense of reason so like don't just
don't question this have faith I abandon
your reason even in to accept
contradictions accept mystic mysticism
accept every other nonsense this is not
the faith we speak about is the faith of
wait I am ill I recognize that much I am
bothered by suffering bothered by greed
aversion delusion so you need to place
faith in a doctor to some extent
otherwise you will not take the medicine
cause you don't trust it and if you
think that that's the ultimate criteria
of not trusting anything and everything
while you're free to do so but then you
will remain liable to greed aversion
delusion that you kind of recognize as
are a problem that must be addressed the
form of illness of course people who are
like purely and
only reasonable and rational they'll
never even accept greed aversion
delusion to be the problem
they've just reason it out but the
reasoning cannot free from suffering
mere reasoning cannot free from
suffering so if you truly only switch
yourself doesn't matter how much how
great your reasoning and rush
is when you suffer you realize that is a
problem and again you can use the reasoning to
and again you can use the reasoning to
realize that suffering is a problem but
most people when it comes to suffering
would use the reasoning to like deal
with suffering not look at it for what
it is so that's why as we spoke before
you need the reasoning like objective
thinking clarity of that rational
thought paired with existential attitude an
paired with existential attitude an
existential idea to means existence is a
problem suffering is a problem and then
you use the rational thought and your
reasoning to unravel how and why is this
existence is a problem and then you
would well it's a problem because we are
not in control because you're subject to
greed a version delusion you're subject
to death accidents sickness aging
unavoidable and those things that are
pleasant so you're subject to suffering your
so you're subject to suffering your
reason is subject to suffer so how do I
approve this how do i cure myself from
that problem not web and earning reason
and pretending yeah you know the
universe universal energy that's all I
need to tap into and I'm done no by
using the reason to find the right
doctor and then by using the reason to
keep applying the instructions from the
right doctor and who is the right doctor
well you have no criteria for that as we
said before but you can use your reason
to determine who is the least likely
gonna be the wrong doctor and then start
applying it
trial and error and then you see is this
diminishing the suffering is this
diminishing liability to be disturbed
I'm not sure well maybe I should apply
more no well hold on if you're not sure
make the effort understand why you're
not sure is it because you haven't
applied enough yes is it because it's
inadequate oh now you discover
contradiction in the doctor's
instruction ah
that's why change the doctor or you
discover contradiction in your
understanding of doctors instruction
change your understanding I'm graded
glad everybody knows you doctor why
should I take this medicine oh well just
yeah what people doing why should I do
that well you like I can't answer that
for you
I can tell you why you shall do it but
that will that cannot be the reason why
you should do it the only reason why you
should do it is if you start seeing your
existence as a problem that's the reason
why you should do it and again then you
question what am I asked to do am I
asked to abandon my reason to abandon my
intellect to sacrifice my basically
rational thought and commit to this
ridiculous like just near faith alone
like salvation no not at all
I'm actually asked to use the reason and
turn it against the existence to the
point of like revealing that underlying
nature of existence which is nature of
suffering and then you will not need any
other proof why you should do it you
would recognize suffering is a problem
we are liable to this it's it's perilous
it's dangerous it's actually worth
escaping from but even that you need to
have reason and faith to arrive at that
mundane conclusion that you should
practice the Dhamma
so that's why yeah you are fortunate if
you already have faith to practice the
Dhamma but that in itself oh yes I faith
that that's the best doctor but are you
now reasonably applying his instruction
no I just hope through my admiration of
doctor and my my belief that he's the
greatest doctor I'll somehow be cured No
so the faith type when the Buddha talks
about is the type that has a lot of
faith so he doesn't necessarily question
the doctor to the same extent but it
doesn't mean he's unreasonable even the
faith type cuz you still need a reason
to apply the principle of the right
method with this this is he has a
sufficient amounts of reason exactly it
wise it exactly so he gets faith that
compensates for maybe slightly lesser
extent of reason but there is two reason
and reasonable attention and recognition
of these things otherwise how can you
find it well you don't know what you
find exactly so that's what I'm saying like
exactly so that's what I'm saying like
being overly rational as in never having
any any degree of faith in regard to it
and seeing that there is maybe a longer
greater perspective hit play or being
liked irrational basically not rational enough
irrational basically not rational enough
which is when your mystical when it's
just when you make statement so it's
just like this this is it
knowing here now it's the present moment
and just be here now in the present what
have you understood there you're just
parroting basically the mantra is their
understanding of the principle behind an
account which you can't suffer or is
just stop thinking stop thinking be here
now just stop thinking just present
moment at present moment so you denying
given the basic reason yeah so that's I
mean not being obtainable but mere
reasoning alone doesn't mean you need to
become unreasonable needs to means me
you need to use the reason to the point
of them near you get the results that
come from beyond reason and what beyond
the reason well it's the repetition of
reason is beyond reason so what you
wouldn't repeat the reason if you don't
see the point of reason such as
mysticism stop thinking be here now and
you won't repeat the reason if you never
abandon your reason is a starting point
to the point of never allow any degree
of faith in regard to it faith means
what you put first basically like I have
a criteria of what the right doctor is
whether the right doctor isn't but the
fact is I'm not cured I'm still sick but
on account of my criteria being put
first as for and foremost I will not
commit to any doctors instruction so
your own reason impeded you to go beyond
reason but if you realize what I have
nothing to lose because I'm not
sacrificing reason I'm not being asked
to do unwholesome things what if I just
for this you know give a benefit of
death to the doctor that is least likely
to be wrong based on my own reasoning
and then follow his prescription and
I'll see if I'm getting better or not I
have nothing to lose
now if I ask you on account of following
my medicine go and do this hideous Act
and he's crazy things but believe you'll
be right then you use your reason that's
what the Buddha referred to like the the
mundane right view recognizing there is
suffering there's a possibility of not
suffering there is get there is action there are
there is get there is action there are
results of action there is the extent of
things that I cannot reasonably know I
cannot reason next life or previous life
but I can also not reason the belief of
there is no next life and there is no
previous life so you like basically the
mundane right view is the transparency
of reason when your reason is not used
to like justify greed aversion delusion
or when your reason is self honest
that's what Monday in Drive view is
honest like I know only to this extent
I don't know that extent that doesn't
mean that I can now justifiably accept
the view and belief for the extent that
I don't know you just need to recognize
reasonably did I don't know this much
but then you also study what is it
important to know this much what is
important to know then the inevitable
question would be why do I want to know
that it's unpleasant for me
the lack of the lack of proof the lack
of belief makes me feel anxious
not knowing so that is the factual
reality that you can reasonably discern
and accept the extent of not knowing
certain things makes me feel anxious
what is the next conclusion I'm subject
to anxiety because if I'm truly my own
in control of myself and I think it goes
anxiety in me yet there are things that
can cause anxiety in me so will I use
now my reason to cover up that anxiety
and jump into belief that there is no
next life we all die we're just elements
Oh will I use my my reason to basically
negate the reason and just develop this
view that everything will work itself
out and everything will be fine and we
are all heading to heaven all will have
use the mundane right view the right
reason and say I am subject to anxiety
that is the negative the hard truth
whichever way I take it the first truth
is I am subject doing that I am subject
suffering things are not in my control
and if you keep your reason on that
transparent level self transparent level
you will look for the way out your
existence is the problem craving is the
problem suffering is the problem data
would have said like suffering
becoming self-aware of suffering rightly
can only result in two things madness
losing a minor economy anxiety or no
both search as in okay who can help me
with this problem who did where is a
medicine that can basically cure me from
this and that's that's the necessary
attitude for the write down my practice
your anxiety is a it's a measure because
that's what people jump into beliefs and
faith and believe in next lives
unreasonably and this belief in in next
lives unreasonably because it's the pain
the discomfort in your neck is actually
the reality is that you can again use
your reason to like uncover is either I
believe another I don't believe I do it
because it displeases me it's unpleasant
that's right the basis so irrationally
you discern that you keep acting out of
discomfort that you are subjected to you
try to get rid of pain that is your
ultimate value to not suffer whether you
pursue the world or try to get rid of
the world you do it cuz you don't wanna
suffer but if your recognition then
stays in that level then you actually
are step closer to understand the nature
of suffering and obviously the escape
from it in the way they will not require
a belief ultimately and for its own sake
believe that's the beliefs that
sacrifice reason are wrong but believes
they make you keep it keep repeating
that which you reason out rightly that's
a good belief that will actually make
you to the work so yeah
faith is necessary that's what the power
of faith but faith faith is also
dangerous because if you haven't reason
clearly enough you can place it in
something very wrong and that is that
the peril of human situation you cannot
run oh you're right until you commit to
that which seems right and then keep
applying it until you get the right
results
and ten years down but again you can use
any reason to recognize that well either
way you're subjected to suffering
subjected to anxiety subjected to
problem so fundamentally you have
nothing to lose your already yeah so you
better apply something and make some
effort to trial and error and hope you
have enough time and just like to do the
work